Adriano Corbelino II

adrianocorbelinoii.com | GitHub | LinkedIn

Várzea Grande, Mato Grosso, Brazil adrianocorbelinoii@gmail.com

ABOUT

I am a Brazilian computer scientist who is constantly thrilled with the impact type systems can have on users. I have experience working with software development and my three main interests are **Type Theory**, **Formal Verification**, and **Systems Programming**.

EDUCATION

Federal University of Mato Grosso (UFMT)

Bachelor in Computer Science with a GPA of 3.59/4.0 (8.84/10).

Cuiabá, Mato Grosso, Brazil Jun 2017 – Oct 2021

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Back-end Developer

2021 - 2022

Acerto

Remote – Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

- I developed, designed, and maintained a diversity of systems for a company that operates in the debt collection
 market.
- Focus on: Improving query performance and creating tools to automate tasks for other employees.
- Tools: C#, Python, and PostgreSQL.

Full-stack Developer Intern

2021 - 2021

Núcleo de Tecnologia da Informação e Comunicação do Instituto de Computação (NUTI-IC)

Cuiabá, Mato Grosso, Brazil

- I developed and maintained a system that manages the reports of POLITEC-MT, a state department that is responsible for providing services requiring forensic skills.
- · Tools: Java, Spring, React, and PostgreSQL.

Full-stack Developer Intern

2018 - 2020

Núcleo de Tecnologia da Informação e Comunicação do Instituto de Computação (NUTI-IC)

Cuiabá, Mato Grosso, Brazil

- I developed and maintained a system that manages the health surveillance data and the dashboards of public health indicators for the Mato Grosso State Health Department.
- Tools: C#, Python, .NET Framework 4.7, ASP.NET MVC, jQuery, Microsoft SQL Server, and Katalon.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Undergraduate Research Assistant

2020 - 2021

Federal University of Mato Grosso

Cuiabá, Mato Grosso, Brazil

- I performed an experiment to evaluate the performance of data augmentation methods in the context of bird calls.
- Tools: Python and Librosa.

Research Assistant

2020 - 2021

Federal University of Mato Grosso

Cuiabá, Mato Grosso, Brazil

- I assisted in the creation of the RSDD[1], a dataset containing satellite data about deforestation in Mato Grosso.
- Tools: Python, Rasterio, and QGIS.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

2018 - 2021

Federal University of Mato Grosso

Cuiabá, Mato Grosso, Brazil

- I assisted in the following courses: Discrete Mathematics, Data Structures, Theory of Formal Languages, Automata
 and Computability (Theory of Computation), Design and Analysis of Algorithms (twice), Compilers 1 (Compiler's
 front end).
- I developed exercise lists, taught review lessons, and offered both group and individual help sessions.

PUBLICATIONS

Conference Proceedings

[1] Rosangela Ventura et al. "RSDD: um Conjunto de Dados para Modelagem de Desmatamentos". In: *Anais do XIV Workshop de Computação Aplicada à Gestão do Meio Ambiente e Recursos Naturais*. João Pessoa/PB: SBC, 2023, pp. 159–162. doi: 10.5753/wcama.2023.230675. URL: https://sol.sbc.org.br/index.php/wcama/article/view/25106.

CREDENTIALS AND PRIZES

- Best Computer Science Senior of 2020/2.
- 2021 ICPC South America/Brazil Finalist.
- TOEFL IBT score of 105/120.
- GRE score of 317 (V: 155/170, Q: 162/170, AW: 3.5/6.0)